lovecrochet.com 2017-10-06

# Privacy Policy | LoveCrochet

The coloured text on the right-hand side of each paragraph provides a short explanation of our Privacy Policy. Hopefully you will find the summaries helpful, but it is important that you find the time to read the Privacy Policy in full. 

## Introduction

We are founded on the principle of ensuring that our customers enjoy the experience of shopping with us. We know that you may be concerned about the privacy of information you share with us. We take the privacy and security of your personal details very seriously and are committed to protecting them. Here we outline our Privacy Policy, which sets out how we handle the information we collect about you when you visit our website and use our services. 

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 11 August 2016. This is the privacy policy for Lovecrafts Collective Limited, incorporated and registered in England and Wales (Company No. 07193527), whose registered office is at 7th Floor, 10 Bloomsbury Way, London, WC1A 2SL, trading via its subsidiaries as loveknitting.com and lovecrochet.com (“Lovecrafts”, “we”, “us”) and who is the data controller for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998. We are committed to protecting and respecting the privacy rights of our online visitors (“you”). 

This Privacy Policy sets out how we will process any information we collect about you or that you provide to us when you access or use our websites or other online or mobile services or applications (“Services”). Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information. Your personal information will not be used or disclosed for purposes other than as set out in this Privacy Policy or which are not permitted under applicable law. This Privacy Policy applies to personal information we hold about individuals, not to information we hold about companies and other organisations. 

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

Our privacy policy may change at any time. The latest version is not the last.

We may change this Privacy Policy at any time, including whenever the functionality of our website requires it be updated. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the “last updated” date above and, in some cases, we may provide you with more prominent notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage or sending you a notification). We encourage you to check back regularly to review this page so that you will always know what information we collect, how we use it, and to whom we disclose it. 

## Information we may collect from you

We collect your order and registration data. Our servers may also collect log and traffic data.

This Privacy Policy applies to any information that you provide to us when using our Services or which we may collect from you automatically, including if you create a member account, subscribe to any of our Services, order any of our products, or upload or submit any material via our websites. By way of illustration, it includes: 

  * Your email and password which you provide when registering for an account.
  * Any information you provide when completing a form on our website, such as your name, email address, postal address, payment details and telephone number. 
  * Details of any transactions made by you through our website and of the fulfilment of your orders. 
  * Communications you send to us, for example to report a problem or to submit queries, concerns or comments regarding our websites or their content. 
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them. 
  * Details of your visits to our websites including, but not limited to, traffic data and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise, and the resources that you access. 
  * “Customer Content” which you submit via your “Public Profile” (as defined in our [Terms of Use](https://www.lovecrochet.com/us/terms-and-conditions.html)). 

## Your personal information and how we use it

We use the collected data to fulfil your orders, to manage our Services and to improve your experience. We will send you emails based on your interactions with us, for instance order confirmation and shipping e-mails. If you consent, we may also send you promotional email alerts and newsletters. We may also use your information to help prevent fraud. 

We use the information we collect about you for the following purposes:

  * To fulfil you order, answer any queries or requests you may have, and carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us. 
  * To identify you when you make contact with us.
  * To prevent and detect fraud. We may check your details with fraud prevention agencies. If you provide false or inaccurate information that makes us suspect fraud, we will record this. 
  * For statistical or survey purposes and market analysis to improve our Services.
  * To ensure that content from our Services is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device. 
  * To administer the Services and, if applicable, your Public Profile.
  * If you consent, to send you marketing that may be of interest to you.*

We may record and monitor communications between you and us to ensure quality assurance and compliance. 

*If you subscribe for our newsletters, create an account on one of our websites or associated mobile applications or otherwise agree to receive marketing from us, we may send you email alerts and or push notifications for new sales event launches, products, features, enhancements, special offers, upgrade opportunities, events of interest, and one-off marketing promotions. Such alerts may include marketing information about us, our subsidiaries or selected business partners. At any time you can unsubscribe from our contact list by following the unsubscribe instructions on communications sent to you, by contacting us or by unsubscribing via your account and disable push notifications by changing the settings on your device. 

## Cookies

We use cookies to personalise your experience with us and improve our Services. They are also used to collect statistical data. 

In order to provide certain of the Services we use “cookies”. These are small text files that a website transfers to your browser for added functionality or for tracking your usage of the website.  Cookies help us to improve our websites and to deliver a better and more personalised service.

For example, we use “session cookies” when you add products to your basket, and also to obtain statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns. These are saved to the browser only and disappear when the browser is closed.  We also use “permanent cookies” to remember if you have visited us before; these will stay on your computer after you leave our website.

On most browsers you can refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies or by clearing your cookies. The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to disable cookies altogether, prevent the addition of new cookies or have a notification sent to you when you receive a new cookie. However, if you disable your cookies, your use of our website or Services may be adversely affected.

For more information about cookies, please visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

## Disclosure of your information

We may disclose your data to our agents and contractors in order to fulfil your order, if required to prevent illegal and fraudulent activities, and to other trusted third parties as set out below. We only pass your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes if you consent.

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * To our affiliates, to providers of our affiliate network services, or to our agents or contractors who assist us in providing the our Services, for example processing transactions, fulfilling requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, analysing data, providing support services or in other tasks, from time to time. Our agents and contractors have strict contracts with us and will only use your information to the extent necessary to perform the services they are providing to us, upon our instructions. 
  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets. 
  * If required to do so by law, or in order to enforce or apply our [Terms of Use](https://www.lovecrochet.com/us/terms-and-conditions.html), [Terms of Sale](https://www.lovecrochet.com/us/terms-and-conditions.html) or other legal rights, or if we believe that such action is necessary to protect the rights, property, or safety of Lovecrafts, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other licensed companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Information held about you by these agencies may be linked to records relating to other people living at the same address with whom you are financially linked. If you need details of fraud prevention or credit agencies from which we obtain and with which we record information about you, please write to us at   
7th Floor, 10 Bloomsbury Way, London, WC1A 2SL, 

We may disclose aggregate statistics about users of our Services to prospective partners, advertisers, sponsors and other reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes. This data will not include any personally identifiable information.

From time to time we would like to be able to pass your information to carefully selected third parties that offer products or services that have been identified as likely to be of interest to you. We will only do this if you have opted-in to receive such communications, for example when you complete a data capture form or placed an order with us. If you have not opted-in to receive such communications then you will only receive marketing communications sent directly from loveknitting.com or lovecrochet.com. After you have opted-in to receive third parties communications, you may ask us at any point afterwards not to share your information with third parties by contacting us at [info@loveknitting.com](mailto:info@loveknitting.com) or [info@lovecrochet.com](mailto:info@lovecrochet.com) as applicable.

## Publicly available information

Please note that if you add any Customer Content to your Public Profile (as defined in our [Terms of Use](https://www.lovecrochet.com/us/terms-and-conditions.html)), or make comments or posts on someone else’s Public Profile on our websites, this will be publicly available to other all users of the website. If you remove such Customer Content, or deactivate your Public Profile it will (after up to 2 working days) no longer be publicly available and it will only be held on our back-up files and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You may request that we delete your Public Profile in accordance with our [Terms of Use](https://www.lovecrochet.com/us/terms-and-conditions.html), in which case all content held on your Public Profile will be first be removed from our website within 7 working days and subsequently may be permanently deleted from our back-up files after a period of 12 months. For more information on deactivating or deleting Customer Content (or deleting your Public Profile in its entirety), whether on your Public Profile or on someone else’s Public Profile, please refer to our [Terms of Use](https://www.lovecrochet.com/us/terms-and-conditions.html). 

## Public forums

Any personal information disclosed on social networking sites becomes PUBLIC.

We also have a presence on a number of social networking sites. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. You should exercise caution when adding Customer Content to your Public Profile (or another’s) or when using social networking sites and never disclose your personal information or any other information which you would not want to be in the public domain, now or in the future.

## External links

This privacy policy covers only our websites, which is [www.loveknitting.com](https://www.lovecrochet.com/us/) and www.lovecrochet.com

Our website may, from time to time, contain links to external sites. If you follow a link to any of those sites, please note that we are not responsible for the privacy policies or the content of such sites and we suggest that you check those policies before you submit any personal data to these websites. We do not provide any personally identifiable customer information to these third-party sites.

## Security

We take the privacy and security of your details very seriously, but any Internet data transmission bears risks. All payment transactions are securely encrypted using SSL technology.

You should bear in mind that submission of information over the Internet is never entirely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of information you submit via our website; any transmission is at your own risk. Any online payment transactions will be encrypted using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology.

We do not store your credit or debit card details, except as follows, and with your consent. 

If you consent (to avoid the need to re-enter these details each time you shop with us, and so make purchasing quicker and simpler), we will store an encrypted token that represents your payment card and will reveal only the last four digits and expiry date of your credit or debit card number when confirming an order. We also display the last four digits of your credit card and card type on your receipt. Only these details are stored on our systems and an encrypted token which is unique to our Website. Your full credit or debit card number is never stored on any of our systems. This token is transmitted to the payment provider during the order processing. If you have chosen not to register your card details with us, we will only store the last four digits for the purpose of our communications with you, but for the purpose of a transaction, the entire card number is, of course, transmitted to the appropriate credit card company to process your order. Security codes (CVC) are never stored and will have to be entered for every transaction.

You should protect your password and your computer from unauthorised access by others, and always make sure you sign off when you finish on a shared computer.

## Storage of your information

By submitting your data, you agree that we may transfer, store and process your information.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ('EEA'), including in countries where you may have fewer rights under local law. It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your information and using our Services, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing outside the EEA. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable law including the Data Protection Act 1998.

## Your rights

You may request us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes and to see the information we hold about you.

The Data Protection Act gives you the right of access to information held about you. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. You also have the right to correct any errors in this information.

## Contacting us

As always, please contact us if you have any concerns.

If you have any questions, comments or requests concerning our Privacy Policy or any requests concerning your personal information, please contact us emailing at [info@loveknitting.com](mailto:info@loveknitting.com) or [info@lovecrochet.com](mailto:info@lovecrochet.com) as applicable or write to us at: 7th Floor, 10 Bloomsbury Way, London, WC1A 2SL.
